[Music]
dairy milk supplies between a quarter
and a half of the daily iodine
requirement in the United States though
milk itself has little native iodine the
milk iodine content is mainly determined
by factors like the application of
iodine containing teeth disinfectants
the iodine residues in milk compared to
originate mainly from the contamination
of the te surface uh the teet are are
sprayed or dipped with like a Betadine
type disinfectants the iodine just kind
of leeches into the milk uh too bad most
of the plant-based milks on the market
aren't enriched with iodine too
fortified soy milk is probably the
healthiest of the plant milks but even
if it was enriched with iodine what
about the effects of soy on thyroid
function it's funny when I search the
medical literature on soy and thyroid
this study popped up a coste effective
way to train residents to do thyroid
biopsies just stick the ultrasound probe
right on top and go to town it turns out
on ultrasound your uh thyroid gland
looks a lot like
tofu anyways the the idea that soy May
influence thyroid function originated
over eight decades ago when marked
thyroid enlargement was seen in rats fed
raw
soybeans though the observation that
people living in Asian countries have
consumed soy foods for Centuries with no
perceptible thyroid toxic effects that
certainly suggests their safety bottom
line there's not seem to be a problem
with people who have normal thyroid
function however soy Foods May inhibit
the oral absorption of Synthroid thyroid
hormone replacement drugs but so do all
foods that's why we tell patients to
take it on empty stomach but you also
have to be getting enough iodine so it
may be particularly important for soy
food consumers to make sure their intake
of iodine is adequate what's the best
way to get iodine for those who use
table salt make sure it's iodized
currently only half of table salt sold
contains iodine and the salt used in
processed foods is typically not iodized
of course ideally we shouldn't add salt
at all dietary salt is a public health
hazard I think this title is a little
over the top dietary salt is the number
one dietary risk factor for death on the
planet Earth wiping out more than 3
million people a year twice as bad as
not eating your
vegetables what's the best source of
iodine then sea vegetables right you can
get a little iodine here and there from
a whole variety of foods but the most
concentrated Source by far with up to
nearly 2,000% of your daily allowance
and just a single gram which is like the
weight of a paper clip seaweed given
that iodine is extensively stored in the
thyroid it can be safely consumed
intermittently meaning you don't have to
get get it every day which makes seaweed
use and a range of foods attractive and
occasional seaweed intake enough to
ensure iodine sufficiency however some
seaweed should be used with caution due
to its overly High iodine content like
kelp too much iodine can cause
hyperthyroidism a hyperactive thyroid
gland a woman presented with a rasing
heartbeat insomnia anxiety and weight
loss thanks to taking just two tablets a
day containing kelp in my last video I
noted how the average urinary iodine
level of vegans was less than the ideal
levels but there was one kelp eating
vegan with a urinary concentration over
9,000 right adequate intake is when
you're peeing out 100 to 199 excessive
iodine intake is when you break 300
9,437 way too
much the recommended average daily
intake is 150 mic grams a day for
nonpregnant non- breastfeeding adults we
may want to stay below 600 on a
day-to-day basis whereas a you know
tablespoon of kelp may contain 2,000
right I'd stay away from kelp because
that's too much and stay away from
hijiki because it contains too much
arsenic here's how much of common
seaweed preparation should give you an
approximate daily allowance two Nory
sheets you can literally just nibble on
them as snacks like I do a one teaspoon
of dul flake egg which you can just
sprinkle on anything one teaspoon of
dried arame which is great for like
adding to soups or one tablespoon of
seaweed
salad if iodine is concentrated in
Marine Foods this raises the question of
how early honim living in Continental
areas could have met their iodine
requirements well here's what bonobos do
perhaps are closest relatives during
swamp visits they all Forge aquatic
herbs
[Music]